http://www.sjsu.edu/privacy/index.php

Emergency Notification: Novel Coronavirus (COVID-19)
For the latest information on COVID-19, visit the Health Advisories website.
Skip to main content
Last Updated: June 24, 2019
San José State University respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it
to the extent possible, subject to applicable state and federal law, through our compliance
with our privacy policies and this Privacy Notice.
This Notice applies to the information that we collect when you visit the SJSU's main
website www.sjsu.edu and other websites that we own or control, and on which we have
linked or referred to this Notice (together, the "Sites"). This Notice describes how this information is collected, processed, maintained,
protected, and disclosed. Unless otherwise indicated on a specific Site, the California
State University is the data controller for all information collected under this Notice.
Contact information for the CSU is listed at the end of this Notice.
This Notice does not apply to information collected from or about current or former
employees, contractors, volunteers, and other workers at SJSU as part of their employment
or working relationship with SJSU.
Except as specifically described, our Sites are operated in accordance with the laws
of the United States. Please read this Notice carefully to understand our policies
and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. This Notice reflects
the University's current practices and may change from time to time, so please check
the Notice periodically for updates.
Personal Information we collect and process
In this Notice, "personal information" means any information that identifies or describes
an individual user of the Sites, including, but not limited to, the user's name, social
security number, physical description, address, telephone number, education, financial
matters, medical or employment history, password, email address, and information that
reveals any network location or identity. If you are located in the European Economic
Area (EEA), "personal information" includes all personal data as defined under EEA
laws (including "sensitive personal information" which is provided enhanced protections
under those laws).
We collect personal information about users only as allowed by law and limit the collection
of personal information to what is relevant and necessary to accomplish a lawful purpose
of the University. We collect personal information (and sensitive personal information)
that you send to the CSU, or permit us to obtain from third parties, for purposes
relevant to CSU operations in pursuit of our academic mission. Examples include information
needed for student admission (including financial aid information), employment, housing
and dining services, online educational programs, research, health services, donor
relations, visa application processing, event registration, parking services, IT usage
and support services, library usage, bookstore operations, and website account registrations.
Our legal basis for processing most of this information is to perform a task in the
public interest or in fulfillment of CSU official functions, including those set out
in the California Education Code and/or Title V of the California Code of Regulations,
or under applicable federal law. Other legal bases for processing information include
processing necessary for contract (e.g., to process parking permit payments), for
legitimate interests (e.g., to send requested information) or consent (e.g., to process
certain sensitive personal information).
User-Provided Information
You may be required to provide personal information to access or use certain parts
of our Sites, or features of our Sites or services, including without limitation,
when you apply for or enroll at one of our campuses or programs, subscribe to a newsletter
or email list, make a purchase or donation, fill out a form, participate in any of
our programs, special events or promotions, contact us with a comment, question or
complaint, etc. If you do not provide the requested personal information, you may
not be able to access or use the features of our Sites or service where such information
is requested.
Depending upon the nature of the transaction, the personal information that you may
provide may include: contact information (name, home or mailing address, telephone
number, social media username/handle, mobile phone and/or email address, etc.); academic
area or interest; financial information (financial aid application history, payment
history, social security number, passport number, credit card number, donation attribution
and amount, etc.); health record information (medical record number), allergies, past
medical history, family history, current medications, current medical conditions)
demographic information (age, birthdate, marital status, income, etc.); and profile
information (admissions date, graduation date, alumni status, student identification
number, username, password, relationship to the University, etc.).
Emails and Social Media Sites
If you correspond with us by email, mail or via social media, we may retain the content
of your communication or social media posting, the email or social media account address
from which it is sent, and our response. We collect information automatically using
technology when you visit our Sites or social media pages or when you open one of
our emails as described in this Notice.
The specific personal information (and sensitive personal information) we collect,
why we collect it, and our legal basis for processing it, is periodically reassessed
in applicable data process flow assessments or Data Protection Impact Assessments,
as relevant.
It is the policy of the California State University to limit the collection and safeguard
the privacy of personal information collected or maintained by the University. The
University's information management practices conform to the requirements of the Information
Practices Act of 1977 (Civil Code Section 1798, et seq.), the Public Records Act (California Government Code Section 6250, et seq.), California Government Code Section 11015.5, the Family Educational Rights and
Privacy Act (FERPA) (20 U.S.C. § 1232g; 34 CFR Part 99), and other applicable laws
pertaining to information privacy. In the event of a conflict between this Notice
and the Public Records Act, the Information Practices Act, FERPA, or other law governing
the disclosure of University records, the applicable law will control.
Any information acquired by the University through the Sites is subject to the limitations
set forth in the Information Practices Act. The University will not distribute or
share electronically collected personal information (as defined in subdivision (d)
of California Government Code Section 11015.5) about users to any third party without
the permission of the user, except in narrow circumstances set forth in this Notice.
The University will not sell any electronically collected personal information to
any third party. Such electronically-collected personal information is exempt from
requests made pursuant to the California Public Records Act (Chapter 3.5 (commencing
with Section 6250) of Division 7 of Title 1).
How we use the information we collect
We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including
any personal information:
To provide you with information that you request from us.
To process application, registration and enrollment requests when you apply, register
or enroll for our campuses, events, programs or services, or otherwise administer
your participation in our events, programs or services, including (without limitation)
study abroad and distance learning, financial aid, housing and dining.
To collect and process donations, gifts and donor information.
To process service requests from students, staff, faculty, and other members of the
campus community, including the facilitation of parking permit and identification
card requests.
To process registration for sports, cultural, educational, and other university events.
To respond to your questions, requests, comments or complaints and determine your
satisfaction with our events, programs and services.
To operate, maintain, and provide to you the features, services, and functionality
of the Sites and its contents, and to monitor and improve our site and the user experience.
To provide information about our University and send you related information including
brochures and other University materials, campus and CSU news, academic notices, updates,
security alerts, special offers, confirmations, and support and administrative messages.
To notify you about changes to our Sites or any services we offer or provide through
it.
To compare and review your personal information for errors, omissions and accuracy.
To prevent, detect or investigate any fraudulent, abusive or illegal act.
To allow you to participate in interactive features on our Sites.
In any other way we may describe when you provide the information.
For any other purpose with your consent.
We may also use your personal information for operational and other lawful purposes
such as security, analytics, operations, fraud detection and prevention, reporting,
making back-ups and legal compliance.
We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: (a) remember information
so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit
the Sites; (b) monitor the effectiveness of our Sites and services; (c) monitor aggregate
metrics such as the total number of visitors and traffic; (d) diagnose or fix technology
problems reported by our users or engineers that are associated with the IP addresses
controlled by a specific web company or ISP; and (e) help you efficiently access information.
At the time we collect personal information, we strive to tell users about the purpose
for which the information is collected as well as the general or specific uses that
we will make of that information.
International transfer of personal information
Personal information provided to us by users outside of the United States may be transferred
to other countries such as the United States, where data protection laws may differ
from those of your home country. By providing us with your information, you acknowledge
that your personal information may be transferred to the United States and processed
on servers within the United States. However, all reasonable steps will be taken to
protect your privacy in accordance with applicable data protection laws.
User Content
Any personal information or content you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Sites
(for instance, any content you post) ("User Content") becomes available to the public via the Sites. User Content includes, but is not
limited to, comments, photos, videos, etc. If you remove User Content, copies may
remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored
your User Content.
We reserve the right to monitor the User Content you post on the Sites and to remove
any User Content for any reason or no reason including, without limitation, if in
our sole opinion, such material violates, or may violate, any applicable law, or to
protect or defend our rights or those of any third party. We also reserve the right
to remove User Content upon the request of any third party.
Cookie Policy
Cookies Information
When you visit the Sites, we may send one or more cookies – a small text file containing
a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer that uniquely identifies your
browser and lets us help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the
Sites. A cookie does not collect personal information about you. We use both session
cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after
you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent
visits to the Sites. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser's
directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser.
You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie
is being sent. However, some features of the Sites or services may not function properly
if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.
Google Analytics
We use a tool called "Google Analytics," a web analytics service provided by Google,
Inc. to collect information about use of the Sites. Google Analytics collects information
such as how often users visit our Sites, what pages are visited, and what other sites
were visited prior to coming to our Sites. We use the information we get from Google
Analytics only to improve the Sites. Google Analytics collects only the IP address
assigned to you on the date you visit the Sites, rather than your name or other identifying
information. Google Analytics will also collect contextual information, such as type
of web browser, type of operating system, browser resolution, and network location,
however we do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics
with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent
cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit
the Sites, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google's ability to use
and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Sites
is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to the Sites
by disabling cookies on your browser, however, please note that if you do this you
may not be able to use the full functionality of the Sites.
Log File Information
Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access
a web page. When you register with or view our Sites, our servers automatically record
certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These
server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol addresses
or other device identifiers, browser information, Internet Service Provider, operating
system, location, date/time stamp, clickstream data, referring/exit pages and URLs,
domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.
Clear Gifs Information
When you use the Sites, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which
are used to track the online usage patterns of our users anonymously. No personal
information is collected using these clear gifs. In addition, we may also use clear
gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients.
California Do Not Track Disclosures
California Business & Professions Code Section 22575(b) (as amended effective January
1, 2014) provides that California residents are entitled to know how a website operator
responds to "Do Not Track" (DNT) browser settings. DNT is a feature offered by some
browsers which, when enabled, sends a signal to websites to request that your browsing
is not tracked, such as by third party ad networks, social networks and analytic companies.
We do not engage in the collection of personally identifiable information about users'
online activities over time and across third party websites when an individual uses
our Sites and therefore do not respond to DNT signals.
How we share your information
We share your information internally at the CSU to facilitate and manage the purposes
listed above, including with third parties whom the University engages to process
your personal information on our behalf for the purposes stated above (such as vendors
who help the University with our marketing, application processing, financial aid
or payment processing, education management, and web hosting). The University may
also share your personal data with government and law enforcement agencies or regulators
(1) to comply with a legal process, subpoena, order or other legal or regulatory requirement
applicable to us; (2) to enforce our terms of use or other policies; or (3) to pursue
available legal remedies or defend against legal claims. We may also share your personal
information with a third party as requested by you if permitted by this and other
University policies and applicable laws and regulations. We will not distribute or
share any electronically collected personal information (as defined in subdivision
(d) of California Government Code section 11015.5) about users to any third party
without prior written permission from the user except in narrow circumstances involving
possible violations of Section 502 of the Penal Code or as authorized under law (including
but not limited to the Information Practices Act), or to assist another state agency
or public law enforcement organization in any case where the security of a network
operated by a state agency has been, or is suspected of having been, breached.
We fully cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our
Sites or services for illegal activities. We may report to law enforcement agencies
any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful. Release of your personal
information for security purposes, as described in this Notice to any person or entity,
including, without limitation, in connection with any government investigation or
litigation, shall be based on a determination made solely by us, as permitted by law
or, for those not in the EEA, exercising our discretion for which you expressly grant
permission to us in accordance with this Notice.
How we protect your information
We take reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the
integrity and security of your personal information against loss, unauthorized access,
and illegal use or disclosure. Such personal information is stored by the University
in secure locations and University staff is trained on procedures for the management
of personal information, including limitations on the release of information. Access
to personal information is limited to those members of the University's staff whose
work requires such access. Confidential information is destroyed according to the
University's records retention schedule. The University conducts periodic reviews
to ensure that proper information management policies and procedures are understood
and followed.
The security of your personal information is important to us, but please remember
that no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is
100% secure. While we strive to use commercially reasonable means to protect your
personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the absolute security of any information
you transmit to the Sites, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission
of information, we make commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of
our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information
may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical,
technical, or managerial safeguards. While we strive to protect your personal information
and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online.
We encourage all individuals to use appropriate safeguards to secure their computers
and the information on those computers. For additional information on online privacy
and security, please see the University's policies and procedures related to Information Security [pdf]; you may also consult with the California Attorney General's Privacy Enforcement and Protection website.
In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security,
we will promptly investigate and notify those persons whose personal information has
been compromised in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in the CSU
Information Security Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.
Links to Other Websites
We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our
Sites nor the information or content contained in them, and we make no warranty, either
express or implied, concerning the content of any such site, including the accuracy,
completeness, reliability, or suitability of them for any particular purpose, nor
do we warrant that any such site or content is free from any claims of copyright,
trademark, or other infringement of the rights of third parties, or that any such
site or content is devoid of viruses or other contamination. We may provide links
to other websites to you solely as a convenience, and the inclusion of linked sites
does not imply endorsement by the University or CSU of any of the linked sites. Please
remember that when you use a link to go from our Sites to another website, our Notice
is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including
those that have a link on our Sites, is subject to that website's own rules and policies.
Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding. We do not ensure the
security of your personal information if you visit websites not belonging to CSU,
nor are we the data controller for any information collected on those sites unless
we specifically state so. We further reserve the right to terminate a link to a third
party site at any time.
Access and choice
We comply with all applicable regulations regarding data retention and deletion of
personal data and retain personal information only for as long as necessary to fulfill
the purpose for which it was collected (including for college operations), for strategic
planning, and to comply with applicable laws and retention requirements. You can ask
to review, update or make changes to the personal information we maintain about you,
or exercise your option of having your personal information discarded without reuse
or distribution, by sending a written request to the postal or email address set out
below. We may take a reasonable period of time to respond. If you request the deactivation
or change of information on our system, such information may be retained in our backup
systems for a period of time subject to technology restrictions, or as a precaution
against systems failures. Some information may be retained for longer periods as required
by law, contract or auditing requirements or as otherwise described in this Notice.
You have the option to decline providing information about yourself online and may
use other methods, such as U.S. mail, to respond to requests for information or to
communicate with us. You may use the contact information listed below to ask about
additional alternatives to providing or obtaining information through use of our Sites.
By providing us your email address, you consent to our use of your email address to
send you Site and service-related notices, including any notices required by law,
in lieu of communication by postal mail. We may also use your email address to send
you other messages, including, but not limited to, newsletters, information on campus
activities, programs and events, legal updates, changes to features of our Sites or
services, or other account information. Where required by law, we will obtain your
consent before sending you specific types of email or other communications.
You can choose not to receive such emails from us by "unsubscribing" using the instructions
in any email you receive from us, or by sending a written request to the postal or
email address set out below. It may take up to thirty (30) business days for us to
process your request. This will not stop us from sending emails about your account
or your transactions with us, or any other service-related email. Opting out does
not affect our communications with you via telephone or mail nor does it affect our
use of your non-personally identifiable information as described in this Notice.
EEA Data Subject Rights
If you are an individual located in the EEA only, you have certain rights with regard
to your personal data collected while you are in the EEA. These rights may include
right of access, right of correction, right to be forgotten, right to restrict processing
of your identifiable personal information, right to notice related to changes/deletion/processing
limits, right to data portability, right to objection, right not to be subject to
decisions based solely on automated processing, and right to withdraw consent. Some
of these rights are restricted by law to information that was collected on the basis
of explicit consent, or are restricted by other conditions (such as necessity for
contract or to comply with the law). You have the right to contact us in connection
with the exercise of your rights under applicable EEA law, which you can do through
the contact information below, or by sending an email to privacy@calstate.edu. We will respond to your written request without unreasonable delay and in accordance
with any deadlines imposed by law. Unless we notify you at the time of your request,
we will not charge you any fee in connection with the exercise of your rights. If
you are not satisfied with our response, you have the right to complain to or seek
advice from a supervisory authority and/or bring a claim against us in any court of
competent jurisdiction.
Changes to Our Privacy Notice
We reserve the right to modify this Notice at any time. It is our policy to provide
notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for other operational
purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous
posting of such notice on our Sites page, as determined by the University in its sole
discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications
to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described
in this Notice. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date active and
deliverable email address for you, and for periodically visiting our Sites and this
Notice to check for any changes.
For changes to our Privacy Notice, it is our policy to post any changes we make on
this page. The date the Notice was last revised is identified at the top of the page.
We will provide notice on the Sites, or at www.sjsu.edu, prior to the effective date
of any change. Your continued use of the Sites after any change in this Notice will
constitute your acceptance of such change.
Contact Us
If you have any questions about this Notice or the practices of our Sites, you may
contact us by writing to digitalprivacy@sjsu.edu
Last Updated Jun 25, 2019
